(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
- My name is Catherine.
Today we've got an
intermediate level lesson for you.
If you're interested in buying furniture
for your house, you should like this lesson.
- Exactly.
We are going to talk about a
ton of different furniture items
that you can get to decorate
your house to make it all nice.
- So we're gonna talk about
a lot of vocabulary today.
Pay attention while you're
listening to some of the pieces
of furniture that we talk about.
We'll be back in a moment
to talk more about them.
(upbeat music)
- How about this floor lamp?
- Fine, just get it.
We have been shopping
for furniture for five hours.
I'm so tired.
- We still need to find
an armoire and a dresser.
- Fine, I'm going to go home and
drop off this nice stand coffee table
and love seat while you
look for the rest of the things.
- Great.
Pick me up in about an hour
because I think I'll also get
a bean bag and a dining set.
- Well, you're at it.
Can you pick up a nicer Kleiner?
I really want one so I can watch TV.
- Recliner?
In my beautifully decorated living room?
I don't think so.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
So now what we're gonna do
is since we have so much vocab,
we're gonna take a look at
this language in two parts.
So now let's go to
language takeaway part one.
- Language takeaway.
- Okay, so everyone's
heard of a lamp, a light.
Now this is something that
you use to read in the dark,
for example, to see in the dark, but in
this case, we have a floor lamp, floor lamp.
So this is a lamp you put on the floor.
- Yes, exactly.
So usually this lamp would be a lot taller.
It'll maybe be like a meter
taller, a meter and a half maybe.
- Okay, so for example,
in your living room next to
your sofa, you might
have a very tall floor lamp.
This allows you to get
more light in the room.
- Right, so sometimes the
center light in your living room
is not enough, you want maybe more light in
the corners, you get a little floor lamp.
Okay, so that's the first item.
Now that we go to the bedroom,
we are getting an arm warm.
- Okay, an arm warm.
This is kind of like a wardrobe.
It's a piece of
furniture we use to keep
clothes in, but usually
they're hanging clothes.
- Okay, so a closet is
usually inside a wall, right?
- Right, so a closet's
a part of your house.
- It's not furniture.
- Right, so an arm warm
is the same as a closet,
but it's not in the
house, like in the walls.
It's outside, it's a piece
of furniture, it's a big box.
- I think a good box.
- Yeah, I could pick it up and move it.
- Okay.
- Yes, so an arm warm is a
tall place to keep clothing.
Usually you hang your clothes, you hang
your shirts and your dresses and your coats.
And moving on, we have a dresser.
Now this seems pretty
straightforward to get dressed.
You have a dresser?
- Yeah, it makes a lot of
sense, but there is a big
difference here between
an arm warm and dresser.
A dresser is usually drawers.
So you keep your sweaters, your shirts,
your socks, your underwear in a dresser.
- Okay, so at an arm warm, as you said,
usually you hang your shirts or your pants.
It's for hanging stuff only.
A dresser is you have different drawers
where you can put your socks, your box or
shorts, and any other things that you keep.
- Exactly.
- Okay, very good.
So two very handy words, and that's
what makes the difference between a closet.
So many people say, oh, it's just a closet.
A closet's different.
- Now a closet is actually
part of your house.
It's a part of the wall, maybe has a door.
And yeah, there's a big difference there.
- Okay, so moving on, we have a nightstand.
It's also usually in the bedroom.
- That's right, so I always wondered,
why is it called a nightstand
and not a daystand?
Well, a nightstand, it makes sense.
It usually has a lamp on it, a light on it.
So when you're in bed and you wanna read,
you have a nightstand next to you to put
your lamps, so you can turn the lamp on.
Usually I also keep my books here.
So when I'm reading, I put my
books down, then I go to sleep.
Some people also keep their glasses
and their alarm clock on a nightstand.
- Okay, it's a small table
that stands next to your bed.
- Very good.
And our last word for language
takeaway part one, we have a coffee table.
- Okay, so with the coffee table, Marco,
we're moving back into the living room.
And in the living room, you have a sofa,
you have some chairs, you need a table.
But you don't wanna big table, you
wanna a small table or a very short table.
This is a coffee table.
- It's called a coffee table.
I'm not really sure why, I
guess, 'cause if you're having
coffee in the living room,
this is where you put the coffee.
- That's right.
And we even have something
called coffee table books.
These are big, beautiful books,
hard-back books that have many pictures
that you put on your
coffee table to look nice.
- It's not for you to
actually read all the time.
- I read them, but it's more important to
look, to use these books to look nice, yes.
- And this is interesting
though, because in many other
countries, they're not
really called a coffee table.
So the direct translation wouldn't
really help you in many cases.
Like I know, I think in Chinese, it's
called a tea table, not a coffee table.
- Makes sense.
- Right.
Like I know in Spanish,
it's just called a center table.
- Okay, so this is
basically the low table you
have in your living
room next to your sofa.
In front of your sofa, actually, so you
can have tea or coffee and read books
or put your feet up
while you're watching TV.
- Not in my house when I was a kid.
- All right, so now why don't we
go back, listen to the dialogue again,
and we'll be returning a
little bit with more vocab.
(upbeat music)
- How about this floor lamp?
- Fine, just get it.
We have been shopping
for furniture for five hours.
I'm so tired.
- We still need to find
an armoire and a dresser.
- Fine, I'm going to go home
and drop off this nice, thin coffee
table and love seat while you
look for the rest of the things.
- Great, pick me up in about an hour,
because I think I'll also get
a bean bag and a dining set.
- While you're at it, can
you pick up a nicer liner?
I really want one so I can watch TV.
- Recliner?
- In my beautifully decorated living room?
I don't think so.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back, so now let's take
a look at language takeaway part two.
- Language takeaway.
- Coming up, we have one of my
favorite phrases in the English language.
I don't know why, I like it so much, but it
is a great name for a piece of furniture.
- A love seat.
- Love seat.
- Okay, okay, so it sounds very romantic.
- It does.
- Well, think about a sofa.
A sofa can be very large.
You can have four or five people on a sofa.
But a love seat is a
small sofa for two people.
- Okay, so that's what
makes the difference, right?
It's a sofa, but only two
people can sit on this.
- That's right, so if it's a big sofa,
it's not a love seat.
- And what about if it's one, 'cause
usually sofa sets, you have a love seat,
a big one, and you have one,
sometimes an individual one.
Do you just call that a chair?
- Yep, a chair, a chair.
- Okay, exactly.
We'll come to it in a minute.
There's a special kind of chair that it
might be, but we're not quite there yet.
First, we have another kind
of chair, which is very special,
and it reminds me a
lot of the 1970s, right?
We have a bean bag, and this
is actually a piece of furniture
that's still very popular in many
places, and it's called a bean bag,
because it's a huge bag
that is filled with beans.
- Right, beans are something soft, and
when you sit on it, it looks like a ball,
but when you sit on
it, it can change shape.
- Right, it molds to what shape you are.
- And usually they're very light,
and a lot of times, I hate to say it,
a lot of times, bachelor's
apartments have these.
That's right, it's
actually very cheap piece
of furniture, and it's
comfortable sometimes.
If you're watching TV, you can just
sit on your bean bag, and watch TV.
Even I know some people may, you
know, fall asleep on a bean bag, as guests.
(laughing)
- I've never slept that well, maybe once,
but I don't remember
sleeping on a bean bag.
I imagine it's quite
uncomfortable about it.
- Yeah, yeah.
- But moving on after a bean
bag, which is good and informal
piece of furniture, we have a
dining set, which is a lot nicer.
- Okay, dining set.
- All right, so a dining
set has many pieces.
You have a dining room table.
- Right.
- You have chairs.
So a set is basically a collection
of a table and chairs together.
- Sometimes I think it
will also include some type
of piece of furniture that's next to the
dining table where you can keep your plates,
and you can keep your
tea cups and all that.
What's that called?
- That's called a buffet,
and that's basically,
it's like a dresser
for your dining room.
- Right, exactly.
- It's got like drawers and
stuff for your plates, your
cups, like you said, and it's
next to the dining room table.
But the dining room set or the
dining set is for the dining room.
It's the table where you eat dinner.
- Okay, very good.
And moving on to that special chair
that I am a big fan of, it's very comfortable
sit on, and it's called a recliner.
- Recliner, so we have
a word here, recline.
It means to lie back, to put your
head back, to get comfortable.
So a recliner is a chair that
you can change the shape of
to make you lie down, flat.
So, you know, when you
sit down, you're sitting,
but what if you wanna
lie down and I'm chair?
This chair lets you do that.
- And it also, from the bottom
part where you feed ours,
a little thing pops up
so you can rest your feet
on top of this little
extension of the chair.
- Okay, so it has a built-in foot rest.
- Foot rest, exactly.
- So it's very comfortable, it's very popular,
if you ever watch the series, friends.
- Oh yeah.
- They have the recliners,
it's very comfortable
to watch sports, for
example, you have your feet.
- Joey has his recliner.
And remember when Joey
and Chandler live together,
they have the two
recliners in front of the TV,
those chairs are recliners,
and they're very, very popular.
- Actually, I think in the United States,
they're very commonly
known by the brand, Lazy Boy.
- That's right, there's a brand,
it's not a kind of furniture,
but it's the name of the brand, it's
Lazy Boy, and they're very, very famous,
you're right, Martha, before
they're reclining chairs.
- Exactly, so Lazy Boy is, you may hear it,
but the real word for
it is called a recliner.
So a lot of interesting
pieces of furniture
there, I think our house
is gonna look amazing,
so why don't we go back and
listen to the dialogue one last time.
- How about this floor lamp?
- Fine, just get it.
We have been shopping for
furniture for five hours, I'm so tired.
- We still need to find
an armoire and a dresser.
- Fine, I'm going to go home
and drop off this nice stand,
coffee table, and Lazy, while
you look for the rest of the things.
- Great, pick me up in about an hour,
because I think I'll also get
a bean bag and a dining set.
- While you're at it, can
you pick up a nicer Kleiner?
I really want one so I can watch TV.
- Recliner, in my beautifully
decorated living room, I don't think so.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
So talking about furniture,
it's very interesting.
How do you take it home?
What do you do?
And in this case, they were
transporting it themselves.
And the guy said, I'm
going to go home and drop
off this nightstand
coffee table and love seed.
So to drop off.
- Okay, this is a great verb, to drop off.
It's a verbal phrase.
So the preposition there is off, not on.
So I could say, for example,
Marco, I'm just going to drop
off my bag at home and then
I'll meet you guys for dinner.
That means I'm going to go to my house
and put down my bag and then I'll leave.
So to drop off is basically to go somewhere
so you can put something in that place.
But it doesn't mean that you're
going to go to that place and stay there.
- Right, so if I say I'm
going to drop off the kids
at school, that means
I'm going to take the
kids and leave them at
school and then go away.
- It doesn't mean you're
going to school yourself.
- Right, exactly.
- So can you drop off the
laundry at the dry cleaners, please?
- Very good, so I'm
going to take the laundry
to the dry cleaners, leave it
there and then go somewhere else.
- So what happens at three o'clock
when the kids are still at school?
- That's right, now we use the opposite
verbal phrase and that is to pick up.
- Okay, drop off, pick up.
- So you go pick up the kids,
you go pick up the laundry.
So this isn't just about picking
something up from a table or the ground,
you can actually use your
car to pick something up.
- Right, you go and retrieve it.
So I'm going to the post
office to pick up my package.
- Very good, so phrases that
you're going to have to use
if you're talking about furniture, if
you're talking about buying something.
And while we're on the topic,
I know that one of the
most popular places to
buy furniture is IKEA,
are you a big fan of IKEA?
- I like IKEA and I love
what they've done for people
who don't want to spend
too much money on furniture.
- Furniture is expensive.
- Furniture is very expensive,
you can spend $5,000 on a sofa.
And so IKEA is a wonderful brand
and I think a wonderful company
because it makes good
looking furniture affordable.
- And it's because you put
it together yourself, right?
- That's right, a lot of things you have
to assemble or put together by yourself.
So you buy it in a box
and then you make it.
- Yeah.
- It's a little bit frustrating sometimes,
but for people like me
and I'm sure people like you,
it's part of the fun is
putting stuff together.
- Yeah, because it kind of feels like
you kind of built it, but you really did.
So it kind of gives you that
false sense of accomplishment.
- It's like I'm in the 19th century
and I could make my own furniture.
So it's very popular.
I've actually, and apart
from having great furniture,
I understand that they
have amazing meatballs.
- They do. Well, I'm a Swedish.
I never get to eat Swedish
meatballs and here in China,
they do have some of the
better meatballs around.
So I would recommend
if you haven't tried them.
Try them, they're pretty good.
- Yeah, go to IKEA.
- Go to IKEA, have
some dinner, let me know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
Do you like IKEA and do
you love their meatballs?
- All right, we'll see you guys there.
- Bye, bye.
(upbeat music)